Guide to the Hervey Allen Papers, 1831-1965 SC.1952.01
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- General Correspondence, 1903-1972; V.
  - Individuals and Institutions, 1903-1972; 1.
    - Whi-Who, 1934-1950 (Box 80, Folder 1-3)
    - Wr-Wz, 1939-1946 (Box 80, Folder 4-5)
    - Yaddo, 1926-1934 (Box 80, Folder 6)
    - Yaddo 1930 Conference, 1929-1930 (Box 80, Folder 7)
    - Yale Review, 1920-1929 (Box 80, Folder 8)
    - Yale University, 1923-1949 (Box 80, Folder 9)
    - Yale University Press, 1919-1949 (Box 80, Folder 10)
    - Y, 1925-1949 (Box 80, Folder 11)
    - Z, 1938-1948 (Box 80, Folder 12)
  - Fan Mail and Requests, 1916-1954; 2.
    This subseries contains correspondence from fans to Hervey Allen. The subject matter of fan correspondence ranges from fact checking, corrections, suggestions, to autograph requests. It also includes solicitations for book plates, speeches, employment, and student research projects. Folders are arranged according to book title and person's last name.
    - Action at Aquila: A-Z, 1937-1946 (Box 81, Folder 1-4)
    - Anthony Adverse: A-C, 1933-1949 (Box 81, Folder 5-11)
    - Anthony Adverse: D-K, 1933-1949 (Box 82, Folder 1-10)
    - Anthony Adverse: L-R, 1933-1949 (Box 83, Folder 1-10)
    - Anthony Adverse: S-Z, 1933-1949 (Box 84, Folder 1-7)
    - Announcements and Invitations, 1919-1940 (Box 84, Folder 8)
    - Autograph Requests: A-B, 1921-1949 (Box 84, Folder 9-10)
    - Autograph Requests: C-M, 1921-1949 (Box 85, Folder 1-6)
    - Autograph Requests: N-Z, 1921-1949 (Box 86, Folder 1-4)
    - Autograph Requests: Circular Letter Answer, 1938 (Box 86, Folder 5)
    - Book Plate Requests, 1928-1948 (Box 86, Folder 6)
    - The Disinherited: A-Z, 1943-1949 (Box 86, Folder 7-10)
    - Fan Mail: Circular Letter Answer (Box 87, Folder 1)
    - Fan Mail: General, 1925-1950 (Box 87, Folder 2)
    - Fan Mail: Unidentified, 1916-1947 (Box 87, Folder 3-4)
    - Governess/Tutor Inquiries, 1935 (Box 87, Folder 5-9)
    - Governess/Tutor Inquiries, 1935 (Box 88, Folder 1-3)
    - Toward the Flame, 1926-1935 (Box 88, Folder 4)
    - Speech Requests, 1933-1935 (Box 88, Folder 5-9)
    - Speech Requests, 1936-1949 (Box 89, Folder 1-5)
    - Student Requests/Interest, 1923-1954 (Box 89, Folder 6-8)
  - Condolences, 1947-1951; 3.
    Correspondence from individuals expressing their condolences to Ann Allen after Hervey Allen's passing in 1949.
    - Academic, 1949-1950 (Box 90, Folder 1-3)
    - Editorial, Literary, or Professional, 1947-1951 (Box 90, Folder 4-6)
    - Personal: A-J, 1949-1950 (Box 90, Folder 7-9)
    - Personal: K-Z, 1949-1950 (Box 90, Folder 10-11)
- Literary Correspondence, 1916-1956; VI.
  In this series exists correspondence that primarily functioned as a mode of communication for Allen's various literary projects, namely his research on Edgar Allan Poe; his affiliation with the Poetry Society of South Carolina and the Bread Loaf School of English; his voluminous correspondence with his main publishing companies - Farrar and Rinehart/Rinehart and Company; his rights management correspondence with multiple international publishers of his work; and his editorial responsibilities on the Rivers of America series. While some correspondence with individual figures located in the General Correspondence may arguably be of literary nature, the material found in this series is thematically concentrated on literary production, while correspondence in the General Correspondence series may include personal correspondence/subject matter.
  - Edgar Allan Poe Material, 1916-1956; 1.
    This subseries consists of correspondence relating to Allen's research and his two publications on Edgar Allan Poe. Allen's extensive research into the works and life of Poe positioned him as an authority on Poe subject matter. He received various requests on information about Poe, including rights and permission use of Allen's publications and other general, little known knowledge about Poe. Included is correspondence with various specialty interest groups including, "The Edgar Allan Poe Club," "The Edgar Allan Poe Shrine," "The Edgar Allan Poe Society," and the "Poe Cottage Committee of the Bronx Society of Arts and Sciences," among others.
    Affiliated materials on the publication of Israfel and Poe's Brother are included, in particular a contentious rights issue with one J.H. Whitty, who tried to "delay and thwart" the publication of Israfel by withdrawing permission to reproduce Poe materials owned by him. This section also features collected material such as pamphlets, newspaper clippings, and articles authored by other writers.
    - General Correspondence, 1916-1933 (Box 91, Folder 1-12)
    - General Correspondence, 1934-1946 (Box 92, Folder 1-17)
    - General Correspondence, 1947-1956 (Box 93, Folder 1-10)
    - Works by Edgar A. Poe (Box 93, Folder 11)
    - Works and Research Relating to Edgar A. Poe (Box 93, Folder 12-14)
    - Places and Monuments Relating to Edgar A. Poe (Box 93, Folder 15)
    - Relating to Israfel (Box 93, Folder 16)
  - Poetry Society of South Carolina, 1921-1940; 2.
    The Poetry Society of South Carolina, a still existent entity, was founded in 1920 by Hervey Allen, Dubose Heyward, and John Bennett. Included in this subseries is correspondence, newspaper clippings and general media, and documents affiliated with the founding and administration of the Poetry Society of South Carolina. Some documents worth highlighting are the establishment of The Blindman Prize, a contest prize named after Allen's poem which awards $250 to a winning poem. Also, correspondence with Amy Lowell and Allen's manuscript, "Elements of Poetry" given at a Poetry Society of South Carolina lecture.
    - General Correspondence, [Undated] (Box 94, Folder 1)
    - General Correspondence, 1921-1924 (Box 94, Folder 2)
    - General Correspondence, 1925-1940 (Box 94, Folder 3)
    - The Blindman Prize, 1921-1925 (Box 94, Folder 4-5)
    - Elements of Poetry Lecture, 1922 (Box 94, Folder 6)
  - Bread Loaf School of English, Middlebury College, 1924-1948; 3.
    Hervey Allen's participation with the Bread Loaf School of English started in 1925, six years after its foundation. John Farrar, Allen's publisher at Farrar & Rinehart, created of the Writers Conference in 1926. Together with Farrar, Allen was featured various times as a lecturer in the annual event along with other notable figures such as Robert Frost, Achmed Abdullah, and Louis Untermeyer. Included in this subseries is affiliated correspondence, documents, press, and notebook (of Allen's) pertaining to various years of the Writers Conference.
    - General Correspondence, 1924-1929 (Box 94, Folder 6)
    - General Correspondence, 1930-1931 (Box 94, Folder 7)
    - General Correspondence, 1931-1933 (Box 94, Folder 8)
    - General Correspondence, 1934 (Box 95, Folder 1)
    - General Correspondence, 1935 (Box 95, Folder 2)
    - General Correspondence, 1936-1939 (Box 95, Folder 3)
    - General Correspondence, 1940-1948 (Box 95, Folder 4)
    - Notebook, 1930 (Box 96, Folder 1)
  - Farrar & Rinehart/Rinehart & Company, 1924-1953; 4.
    Hervey Allen's relationships with his publishers extended beyond the literary and professional. Stanley M. Rinehart Jr. and his wife Fay, Fredrick R. Rinehart (Ted) and his wife Betty, John Farrar and his wife Margaret, were close personal friends of the Allens. Due to the voluminous fanfare and requests Allen received from the public, Farrar & Rinehart publishing company (later Rinehart & Company) acted as a correspondence liaison for Allen, managing his personal and literary finances, forwarding interesting solicitations to him, and corresponding on behalf of him. In 1943, after the death of Stephen Vincent Benét, Allen was appointed to the publishing company's poetry series, Rivers of America (see Rivers of America subseries).
    In this subseries exists business and literary correspondence from Farrar & Rinehart as well as personal correspondence from individuals associated with the publishing company to the Allens regarding financial and personal matters. Notable correspondence includes correspondence between Farrar & Rinehart's Art Editor, Faith Ball, to Hervey Allen about Andrew Wyeth's artwork in Allen's books. The first folder entitled "Summary of Contents" was made prior to the revised 2012 arrangement and it lists individual names and topics found in the correspondence.
    - Summary of Contents (previous arrangement) (Box 96, Folder 2)
    - Farrar & Rinehart, 1924-1930 (Box 96, Folder 3-6)
    - Farrar & Rinehart, 1931-1934 (Box 97, Folder 1-10)
    - Farrar & Rinehart, 1934-1935 (Box 98, Folder 1-12)
    - Farrar & Rinehart, 1936-1938 (Box 99, Folder 1-8)
    - Farrar & Rinehart, 1939-1942 (Box 100, Folder 1-9)
    - Farrar & Rinehart, 1943-1944 (Box 101, Folder 1-9)
    - Farrar & Rinehart, 1945 (Box 102, Folder 1-3)
    - Rinehart & Company, 1946-1947 (Box 102, Folder 4-8)
    - Rinehart & Company, 1948-1953 (Box 103, Folder 1-7)
  - Of Particular Allen Works, 1924-1956; 5.
    This subseries contains correspondence relating to foreign language edition licensing rights of Allen's works. Subject matter may include inquiries about foreign edition misprints and corrections. Correspondence about such subject matter may also be found in the Farrar & Rinehart/Rinehart & Company subseries.
    - General/Multiple Permissions and Rights, 1933-1954 (Box 104, Folder 1)
    - Action at Aquila, 1932-1955
      - American Serial Edition, 1937 (Box 104, Folder 2)
      - Australian Edition, 1932-1934 (Box 104, Folder 3-5)
      - Corrections, 1938-1939 (Box 104, Folder 6)
      - Danish Edition, 1937-1938 (Box 104, Folder 7)
      - Dutch Edition, 1937-1938 (Box 104, Folder 8)
      - English Edition, 1937-1938 (Box 104, Folder 9)
      - Film, 1936-1938 (Box 104, Folder 10)
      - Finnish Edition, 1937 (Box 104, Folder 11)
      - French Edition, 1947-1951 (Box 104, Folder 12)
      - General, 1936-1937 (Box 104, Folder 13-15)
      - General, 1938-1955 (Box 105, Folder 1-4)
      - German Edition, 1937-1949 (Box 106, Folder 1)
      - Hungarian Edition, 1937-1939 (Box 106, Folder 2)
      - Italian Edition, 1938-1955 (Box 106, Folder 3)
      - Norwegian Edition, 1934-1938 (Box 106, Folder 4)
      - Permissions (General), 1938-1940 (Box 106, Folder 5)
      - Polish Edition, 1938 (Box 106, Folder 6)
      - Portuguese Edition, 1947 (Box 106, Folder 7)
      - Radio, 1938 (Box 106, Folder 8)
      - Spanish Edition, 1948 (Box 106, Folder 9)
      - Swedish Edition, 1937-1939 (Box 106, Folder 10)
      - Syndicate, 1938-1939 (Box 106, Folder 11)
    - Anthony Adverse, 1930-1956
      - Corrections, 1933-1937 (Box 106, Folder 12)
      - Czech Edition, 1933-1949 (Box 106, Folder 13)
      - Danish Edition, 1933-1936 (Box 106, Folder 14)
      - Dutch Edition, 1933-1953 (Box 106, Folder 15-16)
      - Editions: 25 cent Edition, (Western Printing and Lithographing Co.), 1948-1950 (Box 106, Folder 17)
      - Editions: 1946 Edition, 1945-1946 (Box 106, Folder 18)
      - Editions: Campaign for $2 Editions, 1936 (Box 106, Folder 19)
      - Editions: Education Edition, 1935 (Box 106, Folder 20)
      - English Edition, 1946 (Box 106, Folder 21)
      - Estonian Edition, 1936 (Box 106, Folder 22)
      - Film, 1933-1935 (Box 106, Folder 23)
      - Film, 1936-1947 (Box 107, Folder 1-3)
      - Finnish Edition, 1934-1936 (Box 107, Folder 4)
      - French Edition, 1933-1949 (Box 107, Folder 5)
      - General, 1930-1935 (Box 107, Folder 6-12)
      - General, 1936-1956 (Box 108, Folder 1-5)
      - German Edition, 1933-1955 (Box 108, Folder 6-8)
      - Hungarian Edition, 1933-1937 (Box 108, Folder 9)
      - Illustrations, 1934 (Box 108, Folder 10)
      - Israeli Edition, 1955 (Box 108, Folder 11)
      - Italian Edition, 1933-1955 (Box 108, Folder 12)
      - Japanese Edition, 1934-1950 (Box 108, Folder 13)
      - Limited Editions Club, 1935-1939 (Box 108, Folder 14)
      - Norwegian Edition, 1934-1936 (Box 108, Folder 15)
      - Permissions (General), 1934-1953 (Box 109, Folder 1-2)
      - Polish Edition, 1940-1944 (Box 109, Folder 3)
      - Portuguese Edition, 1940-1944 (Box 109, Folder 4)
      - Radio, 1934-1950 (Box 109, Folder 5)
      - Romanian Edition, 1938-1940 (Box 109, Folder 6)
      - Sales, 1945 (Box 109, Folder 7)
      - Second Serialization, 1937 (Box 109, Folder 8)
      - Spanish Edition, 1933-1949 (Box 109, Folder 9)
      - Swedish Edition, 1934-1936 (Box 109, Folder 10)
      - Syndication, 1933-1936 (Box 109, Folder 11)
      - Television, 1950-1954 (Box 109, Folder 12)
    - Bedford Village, 1943-1955
      - General, 1943-1955 (Box 109, Folder 13-14)
    - The Blindman, 1924-1951
      - General, 1924-1951 (Box 109, Folder 15)
    - Blood Lust, 1936-1941
      - General, 1936-1941 (Box 110, Folder 1)
    - Carolina Chansons, 1932-1950
      - General, 1932-1950 (Box 110, Folder 2)
    - The City in the Dawn, 1949-1955
      - General, 1949-1955 (Box 110, Folder 3-4)
      - German Edition, 1951-1953 (Box 110, Folder 5)
      - Posthumous Publication, 1950-1951 (Box 110, Folder 6)
    - The Disinherited, 1941-1953
      - Czech Edition, 1945-1948 (Box 111, Folder 1)
      - Danish Edition, 1945-1946 (Box 111, Folder 2)
      - Dutch Edition, 1943-1949 (Box 111, Folder 3)
      - English Continental Edition, 1943-1945 (Box 111, Folder 4)
      - English Edition, 1946-1949 (Box 111, Folder 5)
      - Finnish Edition, 1946-1947 (Box 111, Folder 6)
      - French Edition, 1944-1949 (Box 111, Folder 7)
      - General, 1941-1953 (Box 111, Folder 8-9)
      - German/Swiss Edition, 1943-1951 (Box 111, Folder 10)
      - Italian Edition, 1945-1949 (Box 111, Folder 11)
      - Latin American Edition, 1943-1946 (Box 111, Folder 12)
      - Romanian Edition, 1946-1947 (Box 111, Folder 13)
      - Spanish Edition, 1944-1949 (Box 111, Folder 14)
      - Swedish Edition, 1943-1949 (Box 111, Folder 15)
    - Earth Moods, 1934-1953
      - General, 1934-1953 (Box 112, Folder 1)
    - The Forest and the Fort, 1942-1956
      - General, 1942-1956 (Box 112, Folder 2-4)
      - Norwegian Edition, 1944-1951 (Box 112, Folder 5)
    - New Legends, 1929-1953
      - General, 1929-1953 (Box 112, Folder 6-7)
    - Richfield Springs, 1935-1937
      - General, 1935-1937 (Box 112, Folder 8)
    - Sylvania, 1945
      - General, 1945 (Box 112, Folder 9)
    - Toward the Morning, 1944-1952
      - General, 1944-1952 (Box 112, Folder 10-12)
  - Rivers of America series, 1943-1949; 6.
    The Rivers of America series began in 1937 under the editorial of Constance Lindsay Skinner at Farrar and Rinehart. Throughout its publication run, the series underwent three major publishing companies (Farrar and Rinehart, Rinehart and Co., and Holt, Rinehart and Winston), and various editors. Following the death of Skinner, who was found dead at her desk while editing the sixth volume, The Hudson, Carl Carmer, the same author who wrote The Hudson became a co-editor with Stephen Vincent Benét. After Benét's death in 1943, Allen stepped in as co-editor of the series until his death in 1949. The series published individual volumes written by literary authors, as opposed to historians, about individual rivers of the American terrain and their histories.
    In this subseries are correspondence between Allen and other members of the publishing series, correspondence about accepted or rejected manuscripts, and documents relating to the Rivers of America Radio Broadcast at WBEZ Chicago.
    - Accepted and Contracted Authors, 1943-1949
      - Alabama River, 1948 (Box 113, Folder 1)
      - Ashley and Cooper Rivers (Lord Shaftesbury's Darling), 1943-1946 (Box 113, Folder 2)
      - Blackstone River, 1945-1946 (Box 113, Folder 3)
      - Cape Fear River, 1945-1948 (Box 113, Folder 4)
      - Charges River, 1945-1948 (Box 113, Folder 5)
      - Chattahoochee River, 1944-1949 (Box 113, Folder 6)
      - Colorado River, 1943-1944 (Box 113, Folder 7)
      - Columbia River, 1943-1948 (Box 113, Folder 8)
      - Conestoga River, 1943-1949 (Box 113, Folder 9)
      - Connecticut River, 1943-1947 (Box 113, Folder 10)
      - Everglades River, 1943-1948 (Box 113, Folder 11)
      - Fraser River, 1945-1949 (Box 113, Folder 12)
      - General File, 1943-1949 (Box 113, Folder 13)
      - Gila River, 1948 (Box 113, Folder 14)
      - Gulf Stream, 1947-1949 (Box 113, Folder 15)
      - Housatonic River, 1943-1946 (Box 113, Folder 16)
      - Hudson River, 1949 (Box 113, Folder 17)
      - James River, 1943-1944 (Box 113, Folder 18)
      - Juniata River, 1948-1949 (Box 113, Folder 19)
      - Kanawha River, 1943-1948 (Box 113, Folder 20)
      - Lehigh River, 1944-1946 (Box 114, Folder 1)
      - Louisiana Rivers, 1943 (Box 114, Folder 2)
      - Mackenzie River, 1946-1949 (Box 114, Folder 3)
      - Merced River, 1945 (Box 114, Folder 4)
      - Merrimac River, 1943-1949 (Box 114, Folder 5)
      - Minnesota River, 1946 (Box 114, Folder 6)
      - Missouri River, 1943-1946 (Box 114, Folder 7)
      - Mohawk River, 1943-1948 (Box 114, Folder 8)
      - Muskingum River, 1948 (Box 114, Folder 9)
      - Niagara River, 1943-1947 (Box 114, Folder 10)
      - Ohio River, 1947-1949 (Box 114, Folder 11)
      - Ottawa River, 1943-1947 (Box 114, Folder 12)
      - Platte and Sweetwater Rivers, 1947 (Box 114, Folder 13)
      - Potomac River, 1943-1949 (Box 114, Folder 14)
      - Powder River, 1943-1949 (Box 114, Folder 15)
      - Rancocas River, 1943-1947 (Box 114, Folder 16)
      - Red River, 1943-1948 (Box 114, Folder 17)
      - Rio Grande River, 1943-1948 (Box 114, Folder 18)
      - Rivers of the Alaskan Panhandle, 1945 (Box 114, Folder 19)
      - Rivers of the Eastern Shore, 1943-1948 (Box 114, Folder 20)
      - Salinas River, 1943-1945 (Box 114, Folder 21)
      - Saskatchewan River, 1947-1949 (Box 114, Folder 22)
      - Savannah River, 1943-1949 (Box 114, Folder 23)
      - Schuylkill River, 1947-1948 (Box 114, Folder 24)
      - Shenandoah River, 1943-1946 (Box 114, Folder 25)
      - St. Croix River, 1943-1945 (Box 115, Folder 1)
      - St. John's River of New Brunswick, 1948 (Box 115, Folder 2)
      - St. Mary's River, 1948-1949 (Box 115, Folder 3)
      - Tennessee River, 1943-1948 (Box 115, Folder 4)
      - Upper Mississippi River, 1943 (Box 115, Folder 5)
      - White River, 1945 (Box 115, Folder 6)
      - Winooski River, 1947-1949 (Box 115, Folder 7)
      - Yazoo River, 1947-1948 (Box 115, Folder 8)
      - Yukon River, 1943-1948 (Box 115, Folder 9)
    - Considered or Rejected Authors, 1943-1949
      - A, 1945 (Box 115, Folder 10)
      - B, 1943-1949 (Box 115, Folder 11)
      - C, 1944-1948 (Box 115, Folder 12)
      - D, 1945-1949 (Box 115, Folder 13)
      - E-F, 1944-1948 (Box 115, Folder 14)
      - G, 1944-1948 (Box 115, Folder 15)
      - H-J, 1943-1949 (Box 115, Folder 16)
      - K-L, 1944-1949 (Box 115, Folder 17)
      - M, 1943-1949 (Box 116, Folder 1)
      - N-O, 1943-1948 (Box 116, Folder 2)
      - P-Q, 1945-1949 (Box 116, Folder 3)
      - R, 1944-1948 (Box 116, Folder 4)
      - S, 1944-1949 (Box 116, Folder 5)
      - T-V, 1944-1949 (Box 116, Folder 6)
      - W, 1943-1949 (Box 116, Folder 7)
      - Y-Z, 1943-1945 (Box 116, Folder 8)
    - Interoffice Correspondence, 1943-1949
      - Interoffice Correspondence, 1943-1944 (Box 116, Folder 9-10)
      - Interoffice Correspondence, 1945-1949 (Box 117, Folder 1-6)
    - Radio Broadcasting Programs, 1945 (Box 117, Folder 7)
- Projects, 1932-1949; VII.
  Beside a prolific literary career, Allen dedicated his life to numerous roles outside of writting including various academic, government, and even inventor occupations. Featured in this series are documents that demonstrate Allen's involvement with various academic institutions including the University of Miami (then Miami University), St. John's College, Cazenovia Junior College, Ransom School, and Washington and Jefferson College; his tenure as Regional Information Representative in the US War Manpower Commission at Atlanta, Georgia; and documentation of a machine he invented called the "Tangential Engine."
  - Miami University (University of Miami), 1932-1949; 1.
    Hervey Allen had a number of diverse roles at the University of Miami. He lent his name and support to the development of various literary programs, like the Winter Institute of Literature and the Hispanic-American Institute. Allen was also influential in the establishment of the then nascent University, serving as a member of its Board of Trustees, the Committee on Development, and other various administrative roles. Featured in this subseries is correspondence with other influential individuals at the University such as Dr. Bowman F. Ashe. Due to the overlapping nature of the material, some material has been filed under one individual's folder, though it may also involve other individuals who have assigned folders of their own.
    - Ashe, Dr. Bowman F., (President), 1940-1949 (Box 117, Folder 8)
    - Board of Trustees, 1938-1949 (Box 117, Folder 9)
    - Committee on Development, 1939 (Box 117, Folder 10)
    - Dorean Tharp, Charles, (Dean, College of Liberal Arts), 1949-1950 (Box 117, Folder 11)
    - General Correspondence, Undated, 1938-1947 (Box 118, Folder 1)
    - General Correspondence, 1948 (Box 118, Folder 2)
    - General Correspondence, 1949 (Box 118, Folder 3)
    - General Correspondence: Booklets and Pamphlets, 1948-1950 (Box 118, Folder 4)
    - Harkins, William G., (Librarian), 1948-1949 (Box 118, Folder 5)
    - Hispanic-American Institute, 1933-1949 (Box 118, Folder 6)
    - Lowe Memorial, 1939-1941 (Box 118, Folder 7)
    - Marine Laboratory: Correspondence with F.G. Walton Smith, 1946-1949 (Box 118, Folder 8)
    - Marine Laboratory: Preliminary Sketches of Laboratory by Marion I. Manley, 1944 (Box 118, Folder 9)
    - Marine Laboratory: Reports, 1945-1949 (Box 118, Folder 10)
    - Pan American Affairs, 1943-1945 (Box 119, Folder 1-2)
    - Pan American Affairs, 1946-1949 (Box 119, Folder 3)
    - Rasco, R.A., (Dean, School of Law), 1947-1949 (Box 119, Folder 4)
    - Ross, Malcolm, (University Editor), 1947-1949 (Box 119, Folder 5)
    - Winter Institute of Arts and Sciences, 1943-1944 (Box 119, Folder 6-8)
    - Winter Institute of Literature, 1932-1946 (Box 120, Folder 1-4)
  - St. John's College, 1938-1949; 2.
    As a member of the Board of Visitors and Governors, Allen played a vital role in the administration of the College. He lent his name to the College in order to procure endowments and establish other fundraising groups such as founding the Friends of St. John's. He helped reconfigure their education program and promote St. John's achievements and programs by writing articles in the local newspaper and other publications such as the Atlantic Monthly. Included in this subseries is correspondence between the College and the Department of Navy, who wanted to expand the Naval Academy by purchasing part of St. John's campus. Due to the overlapping nature of the Committee of Development, Resource Committee, and Board of Visitors and Governors these materials are all filed under the latter's name.
    - Books and Pamphlets, 1939-1944 (Box 120, Folder 5)
    - Books and Pamphlets, 1949 (Box 120, Folder 6)
    - Board of Visitors and Governors, October 1938 - September 1939 (Box 120, Folder 7)
    - Board of Visitors and Governors, October 1939 - December 1940 (Box 120, Folder 8)
    - Board of Visitors and Governors, April 1941 - December 1946 (Box 120, Folder 9)
    - Board of Visitors and Governors, 1947 (Box 121, Folder 1)
    - Board of Visitors and Governors, January - April 1948 (Box 121, Folder 2)
    - Board of Visitors and Governors, May - December 1948 (Box 121, Folder 3)
    - Board of Visitors and Governors, 1949 (Box 121, Folder 4)
    - Education, Undated, 1939-1949 (Box 121, Folder 5)